{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What is a lambda function?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "A function with a name",
        "b": "A function without a name",
        "c": "A built in python function",
        "d": "A recursive function"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which keyword is used to define a lambda function?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "lambda input:output",
        "b": "input:lambda output",
        "c": "def input output",
        "d": "output:lambda input"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Python function is used to apply a lambda function to every element of an iterable?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "apply()",
        "b": "call()",
        "c": "map()",
        "d": "reduce()"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of filter function in python?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "To apply a condition to an iterable and get a filtered output",
        "b": "To remove duplicates from a iterable ",
        "c": "To sort an iterable in ascending order",
        "d": "To reverse the elements the elements of an iterable"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a correct example of a lambda function that takes two input parameters and returns their sum?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "lambda x,y:x*y",
        "b": " lambda x,y:x-y ",
        "c": " lambda x,y:x**y ",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": " Which Python function is used to apply a condition to an iterable and get a filtered output? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "map()",
        "b": "reduce()",
        "c": "filter()",
        "d": "apply()"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": " What is the output of the following lambda function?\nlambda x: x.upper() ",
      "answers": {
        "a": " Converts a string to lowercase ",
        "b": " Converts a string to uppercase ",
        "c": " Removes whitespace characters from a string ",
        "d": " Converts a string to title case "
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": " Which Python module is used to use the reduce function? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "functools",
        "b": "itertools",
        "c": "math",
        "d": "random"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": " Which of the following is a correct example of using the map function with a lambda function to double each element of a list? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": " map(lambda x: x/2, [1, 2, 3, 4]) ",
        "b": " map(lambda x: x**2, [1, 2, 3, 4]) ",
        "c": " map(lambda x: x+2, [1, 2, 3, 4]) ",
        "d": " map(lambda x: x*2, [1, 2, 3, 4]) "
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "what will be the output of the following code: \nimport functools\nlist_of_numbers = [1, 2, 3, 4]\nresult = functools.reduce(lambda x, y: x*y, list_of_numbers)\nprint(result) ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "10",
        "b": "24",
        "c": "12",
        "d": "Error"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "what would be the output of the following code?\nvegetables = ['brinjal', 'potato', 'tomato', 'palak', 'methi']\nfiltered_veg = list(filter(lambda x: 't' in x, vegetables))\nprint(filtered_veg) ",
      "answers": {
        "a": " ['tomato'] ",
        "b": " ['brinjal', 'potato', 'palak', 'methi'] ",
        "c": " ['palak'] ",
        "d": "['potato', 'tomato', 'methi'] "
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "What would be the output of the following code?\nmy_list = [1 ,2 ,3 ,4]\nresult = list(map(lambda x: x**2 if x%2==0 else x, my_list))\nprint(result) ",
      "answers": {
        "a": " [1, 4, 3, 16] ",
        "b": " [1, 4, 9, 16] ",
        "c": "[2, 4, 6, 8] ",
        "d": "[1, 2, 3, 4]"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "what is the output of the following code?\nnames = ['Alice', 'Bob', 'Charlie', 'Dave', 'Eve']\nreversed_names = list(map(lambda x: x[::-1], names))\nprint(reversed_names)",
      "answers": {
        "a": "['ecilA', 'boB', 'eilrahC', 'evaD', 'evE']",
        "b": "['Eve', 'Dave', 'Charlie', 'Bob', 'Alice']",
        "c": "['A', 'B', 'C', 'D', 'E']",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    }
  ]
}